Yuan Hou UI/UX Designer

Prisbane, Australia

k619tw.github.io/yuanhhou

k619tw@icloud.com

(+61) 0435222223

Specialises in HCl and UX design to bring better usability and accessibility to the product. Solid background in user interface software and web design framework such as Figma, Protopie, Adobe Suite, and Bootstrap. Experiences in motion graphic, 3D modelling, and interaction design such as Arduino, Adobe After Effects and Premiere Pro, Cinema 4D, and Unity.

Skills

UX Research Method UI Design HCI Research User Testing Advanced Interactive Prototype Front-End Development

Web Design 3D Modelling & Animation Motion Graphics Visual Effects Design Video/Photo Editing Sound Design

Highlight Projects

Aug 2020 - Nov 2020

UX Designer in Finding Green

- Collaborated with four IT background students from The University of Queensland
- Created the user flow and the user journey of the web-based application
- Handoff the design specs to the web developers
- Updated the CSS elements to achieve the dark mode feature
- Worked together with other designers in our team on low-fidelity prototype

Feb 2020 - Jun 2020

UI/UX Designer in Moovie

- Collected qualitative and quantitative data from the interviewees
- Designed low, medium, and high fidelity prototype during the research
- Analysed users' feedback and address their pain points through UX research methods
- Applied design theories and HCl principles in the user interface

Sep 2019 - Oct 2019

UI Lead, Web Designer, and UX Assistant in EcoHub

- Collaborated with three RMIT digital media design students
- Communicated with UX Lead regarding the design specs
- Developed the website structure independently
- Designed the user interface, mockups, concept image, and high-fidelity prototype

Work Experience

Sep 2018 - Jan 2019

Military Service in Chiayi, Taiwan

After finished the undergraduate studies, I had the opportunity to fulfill my mandatory military service for four months in Chiayi, Taiwan. I have learnt how to clean, assemble, and disassemble the rifles, and the shooting skills during the military service. This experience has scaffolded my encouragement and leadership.

Aug 2017 - Aug 2017

Volunteer at Taipei City Government

I was lucky enough to have the privilege of serving the international athletes as a volunteer during the Summer Universiade 2017 in Taipei, Taiwan. I assisted the police officer to scan the international athletes' belongings at the gate of the athletes' village.

Apr 2017 - Aug 2017

Digital Designer at Shih-Chien University

To assist the school of management at Shih-Chien University in promoting the five-day English-Taught camp *COOL CAMP*, I designed the promotional videos, posters, and camp clothes for more than thirty participants (students, staffs, and professors).

Education

The University of Queensland

UI/UX Related Course

Master of Interaction Design

DECO7250 (Human-Computer Interaction): Distinction

Brisbane, Australia

DECO7140 (Introduction to Web Design): High Distinction

Feb 2020 - Nov 2021 (Expected)

DECO7180 (Design Computing Studio 1 - Interactive Technology): Distinction

DECO6500 (Advanced Human-Computer Interaction): High Distinction

RMIT University

UI/UX Related Course

Design Related Course

Bachelor of Design (Digital Media)

COMM2749 (Digital Media Studio 1: Production): Distinction

Melbourne, Australia

GRAP2588(Digital Media Studio 2: Collaboration): High Distinction

Feb 2019 - Nov 2019

OART1013 (Interactive Media 1): Distinction

Shih-Chien University

Bachelor of Business Administration

Web-Assisted Language Learning: High Distinction

Taipei, Taiwan

Post-Production-Visual Effects and Editing: Distinction

Sep 2014 - Jun 2018